Inventory of the Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Collection, 1937 - 1977; bulk 1970-1975
Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Collection1937 - 1977; bulk 1970-1975
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Tobias, Sheila.
1000-67
17.5
43
In 1970, Sheila Tobias became associate provost at Wesleyan University. Her primary administrative focus was on helping Wesleyan make the transition to coeducation for a second time (the first period of coeducation was 1872-1909), which began in 1968. This included the hiring of women faculty and other key personnel. She also co-organized a New England-wide Higher Education Resource Service for women academic professionals, which later grew into the HERS Bryn Mawr Summer Institute for Women in Higher Education Administration. She taught American Studies 210, "Gender and Politics," "Men and Women in Wartime." In 1978, she left Wesleyan to become director of the Math Anxiety (training trainers/dissemination) Project, Washington School of Psychiatry.
The Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Files contain documentation related to feminism, gender issues, and women's studies. It consists of Series 1: Authors Files, which generally includes articles, journals, reprints, and other published materials arranged by author's last name; and Series 2: Subject Files, arranged topically.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Biographical Note
Sheila Tobias was born in Brooklyn, New York, on April 26, 1935. She received a B.A. in history and literature from Radcliffe College in 1957, and an M.A. and M. Phil. in history from Columbia University in 1961 and 1974, respectively.
During the early 1960s, Tobias held positions in journalism and education. From 1967 to 1970, she was assistant to the vice president for Academic Affairs at Cornell University, with special emphasis on implementing the Kahn-Bowers report on undergraduate education. As part of what was first thought to be a "January Term" activity, she launched one of the first women's studies courses later to become one of the first women's studies programs in the country.
In 1970, she became associate provost at Wesleyan University. Her primary administrative focus was on helping Wesleyan make the transition to coeducation for a second time (the first period of coeducation was 1872-1909), which began in 1968. This included the hiring of women faculty and other key personnel. She also co-organized a New England-wide Higher Education Resource Service for women academic professionals, which later grew into the HERS Bryn Mawr Summer Institute for Women in Higher Education Administration. She taught American Studies 210, "Gender and Politics," "Men and Women in Wartime." In 1978, she left Wesleyan to become director of the Math Anxiety (training trainers/dissemination) Project, Washington School of Psychiatry.
Since 1978, Tobias has worked as an educational consultant, engaging in a research and writing assignment for the Research Corporation, working for the Sloan Foundation in its development of the professional science master's degree, and conducting a long term association with the Universities of Leiden and Amsterdam in the Netherlands, among many other activities.
Collection Overview
The Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Files contain a wealth of information related to feminism, gender issues, and women's studies. The earliest document is from the 1937, but the bulk of the material is from 1969-1975, and coincides with Tobias's position as associate provost at Wesleyan University. There is a smaller amount of material from 1975-1977.
Collection Arrangement
The Sheila Tobias Women's Studies Collection consists of two series:
Series 1: Authors Files, which generally includes articles, journals, reprints, and other published materials arranged by author's last name.
Series 2: Subject Files, arranged topically.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Tobias, Sheila.; Women's studies.; Women--United States--History.; Women's rights.; Feminism.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Administration.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series 1: Authors Files
  - Adams, Margaret, The Single Woman in Today's Society: a Reappraisal, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Aldous, Joan, Occupational Characteristics and Males' Role Performance in the Family, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Rhetta, Women of the Convicted Class, 1971, Center for Women's Studies (Box 1)
  - Allen, Pamela, 1965-1971 (Box 1)
  - The Quality of ERA's Equality, American Bar Association Journal undated (Box 1)
  - Changing Sexist Practices in the Classroom, American Federation of Teachers (Box 1)
  - Amundsen, Kirsten, Feminism and Woman's Studies: Survival in the 1970s (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Debbie, The Daughter of the Dream, 1972 (Box 1)
    Student paper on Emma Goldman.
  - Anderson, Eugenie (Ambassador) biographical sketch, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Andreas, Carol, Notes on the Liberation of Women, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Aphra, vol. 1 no. 4, 1970: Free Women: The Family (Box 1)
  - Aphra, vol. 2 no. 2, 1971: The Whore Issue (Box 1)
  - Aphra, vol. 2 no. 3, 1971: Free Women: Passion, Pain, Progress (Box 1)
  - Arthur, Marilyn, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Greece and Rome: The Origins of the Western Attitude Toward Women
    - Women in Ancient Greece: The Ninth through the Sixth Centuries
  - Asimov, Isaac, Uncertain, Coy, and Hard to Please, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Colleges, Project on the Status and Education of Women undated (Box 1)
    2 folders.
  - Astin, Helen S., Women's Studies in American Colleges and Universities, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Atkins, Annette, Eve and Mary: Women and Witchcraft (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, T. Grace, Notes from 1968, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Attwood, C., Women in Fellowship and Training Programs, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Auletta, Ken, Senator Bella - Seriously, New York Magazine, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Baker, Jeff, Science, Birth Control, and the Roman Catholic Church, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Balswick, Jack O. and Charles W. Peck, The Inexpressive: A Tragedy of American Society, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bandura, Albert, Behavior Theory and the Models of Man, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Banner, Lois, 1971 (Box 2)
    - On Writing Women's History, Journal of Interdisciplinary History
    - Why Women Have Not Been 'Great Chefs': an Exploration in the History of Women
  - Bardwick, Judith M., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Readings in the Psychology of Women
    - Women's Liberation: Nice Idea but it won't be Easy
  - Baker-Benfield, Ben, The Spermatic Economy: A Nineteenth Century View of Sexuality, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Herbert, Cross Cultural Perspectives on How to Minimize the Adverse Effect of Sex Differentiation, Know, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Bern, Sandra L. and Daryl, We're All Nonconscious Sexists, Psychology Today, November 1970 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Herbert, Cross Cultural Perspectives on How to Minimize the Adverse Effect of Sex Differentiation, Know, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Barry, Kathleen, The Fear of Feminism of What Makes Women's Liberation Laugh, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Bart, Pauline, Depression in Middle-Aged Women: Portnoy's Mother's Complaint undated (Box 2)
  - Bartolome, Fernando, Executives as Human Beings, Harvard Business Review, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Baruch, Grace (Box 2)
    - The Changing Perception of Feminine Competence
    - The Development of Girls' Sex-Role Attitudes, 1973
    - Implications and Applications of Recent Research on Feminine Development, 1975
    - Maternal Career-Orientation as Related to Parental Identification in College Women, 1973
    - Maternal Influences Upon College Women's Attitudes Toward Women and Work, 1972
    - Maternal Role Pattern as Related to Self Esteem and Parental Identification in College Women
    - Recent Research in Psychology Relevant to the situation of Women
  - Bass, Bernard, Judith Krussel, and Ralph Alexander: Male Managers' Attitudes Towards Working Women (Box 1)
  - Batorewecz, Valerie, 1964, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - The Educated Nurse
    - Welcome to Environ A: Your Plastic World
    - Artist, Musician, Poet Designs Housing Systems
    - The Strange Structure called Environ A
    - Women Make Names in Architecture
  - Battle-Sister, Ann, Conjectures on the Female Culture Question, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bazin, Nancy Topping, Virginia Woolf's quest for Equilibrium, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bem, Sandra and Daryl, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Sex-Segregated Want Ads: Do They Discourage Female Job Applicants?
    - Training the Woman to Know Her Place: The Social Antecedents of Women in the World of Work
  - Bender, Marilyn, A Good Woman is Hard to Find and Behavioral Differences Stressed Women's Management Training, 1972, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Bennis, Watten, Leadership: A Beleagured Species? And The Pornography of Everyday Life, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Benson, Lee Grace, Some Images of Women in the Visual Arts (Box 2)
  - Benson, Ruth Crego, The Backlash (Box 2)
  - Benston, Margaret, The Political Economy of Women's Liberation, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Berger, Arthur A., Dogwood in the American Psyche, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Berger, Arthur A., Women and Advertising: Selling with Sex (Box 2)
  - Berger, Peter and Hansfried Kellner, Marriage and the Construction of Reality (Box 2)
  - Bergman, Barbara and Irma Adelman, 1973, 1971 (Box 2)
    - A Policy Agenda for Women's Economic Problems
    - The 1973 Report of the President's Council of Economic Advisors: The Economic Role of Women
    - The Economics of Women's Liberation
  - Bernard, Jessie (Box 2)
    - Age, Sex and Feminism
    - Changing Family Lifestyles: One Role, Two Roles, Shared Roles
    - Escape from the Doll's House: Women in Graduate and Professional Schools of Education
    - The Impact of sexism and racism on employment status and earnings
    - Sex Differences: An overview
    - Women, Marriage and the Future
  - Berry, Betty (coordinator), 1970 (Box 3)
    - Draft Proposal for a Marriage Insurance Plan
    - Report of NOW Marriage and Divorce Committee
    - The NOW Equal Rights Divorce Reform Bill
  - Berkelsen, Judy, Sex Differences in Political Attitudes and Political Behavior, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno, Growing Up Female (Box 3)
  - Blanco, Dorothy, Psychology and Women: a Review of the Literature (Box 3)
  - Bier, Karen, What Now? 1970 (Box 3)
  - Biller, Henry, Sex Role Learning: Some Comments and Complexities from a Multidimensional Perspective, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Black, Gregory and Clayton Koppes, What to Show the World: the Office of War Information and Hollywood, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Black, Max, Is Scientific Neutrality a Myth? 1975 (Box 3)
  - Black... (Box 3)
    - Black Reconstruction
    - Black Mobility
    - Social Status in the Black Community
  - The Black Scholar, The Black Woman and the Black Male, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Booth, Alan, Sex and Social Participation, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Baskin, Michael J., The Effects of Government Expenditures and Taxes on Female Labor, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Bowman, G.W, N.B. Worthy, and S. Greyser, Are Women Executives People? 1965 (Box 3)
  - Boylan, Donna, Women's Caucus to Wield Some 'Professional Clout' 1972 (Box 3)
  - Boyle, M.B., Equal Opportunity for Women is Smart Business 1973 (Box 3)
  - Bradstreet, Anne, Denise Leverton, and Anne Sexton, Poems, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Bridenthal, Renate, Beyond Kinder, Kuche, Kirche: Weimar Women at Work/ The Greening of Germany, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Broverman, Inge and F. Donald Clarson, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Sex-Role Stereotypes and Clinical Judgements of Mental Health
    - Sex-Role Stereotypes and Self Concepts in College Students
  - Brown, Barbara, Thomas Emerson, Gail Falk, Ann Freedman, The Equal Rights Amendment: A constitutional Basis for Equal Rights for Women, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Victoria, Uncommon Lives of Common Women (Box 3)
  - Brownmiller, Susan,... Woman is Often Her Own Worst Enemy-the Enemy Within (Box 3)
  - Bruner Script, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Brush, Lorelai, Choosing a Women's College (Box 3)
  - Bryan, James H., Apprenticeships in Prostitution (Box 3)
  - Bryant, Becky, Howe Speaks on Education of Traditional Sex Roles (Box 4)
  - Bunting, Mary I., Patricia A. Graham and Elga R. Wasserman, Academic Freedom and Incentive for Women, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Bunzel, John H., Do Colleges Practice Reverse Bias, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Burkhart, Kitsi, Women in Prison (Box 4)
  - Burstyn, Joan N., 1968, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Brain and Intellect: Science Applied to a Social Issue, 1860-1875
    - Religious Arguments Against Higher Education for Women in England, 1840-1890
    - Striving for Equality:Higher Education for Women in the U.S. since 1900
    - American Society During the 1890s: the Woman Question
  - Bysiewicz, Shirley R. (Box 4)
    - CT Law Review-Maried Women's Surnames, undated (Box 4)
    - Maried Women v. Husband's Names, undated (Box 4)
    - Maried Women's Surnames, undated (Box 4)
  - Bysiewicz, Van de Mark (Box 4)
    - The Legal Status of the Dakota Indian Woman, 1975 (Box 4)
    - Women Lawyers in Connecticut: A Survey, undated (Box 4)
  - Calderone, Mary, It's Really the Men Who Need Liberating, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Califano, Joseph A., Memorandum from department of Health Education, and Welfare, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Cameron, Mary Owen, An Interpretation of Shoplifting, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Cambi, Jane M., Women in Utopian Life and Literature, undated (Box 4)
  - Carden, Maren Lockwood, Oneida: Utopian Community to Modern Corporation, undated (Box 4)
  - Carpenter, Liz and Elly Peterson, Letter in Support of the ERA, undated (Box 4)
  - Carr, Catherine and Ann C. Hill, Conference on the Family and Family Law, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Carrol, Berenice, Liberating Women’s History: Theoretical and Critical Essays, undated (Box 4)
  - Cattonar, Joanna, Poems, undated (Box 4)
  - Chandrasekhar, Sripate, Sterilization and Contraception, undated (Box 4)
  - Charton, Linda, Women’s Equality Still in the Future, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Change, Notre Dame’s Father Hesburgh, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Change Reports, Race, Sex, and Jobs, undated (Box 4)
  - Chapman, Jane, 1973, Employment-Related Programs with Impact on Women in Selected Western Countries, undated (Box 4)
  - Chase, Judy, Women Protest Sex Discrimination, undated (Box 4)
  - Chester, Phyllis (Box 4)
    - Women and Madness: New York Times Book Review, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Men Drive Women Crazy undated (Box 4)
  - Childbirth Conference, Proceedings of the first international Childbirth Conference, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Christensen, Ethlyn, Household Employment: Restructuring the Occupation, undated (Box 4)
  - Clarkson, F., S. Vogel, I. Broverman, etc., Family Size and Sex-Role Stereotypes, undated (Box 4)
  - Clemmont, The Black Male Personality, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Bobbi, An Evaluation of Chinese Children’s Books, undated (Box 5)
  - Cohen, Muriel L., An Academic Inquiry, 1973 (Box 5)
  - College English, Women in the Colleges: Status, Teaching Feminist Criticism, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Collins, Randall, A Conflict Theory of Sexual Stratification, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Colorado, Letter and Syllabus, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Condry, John and Sandra, The Development of Sex Differences: A Study of the Eye of the Beholder, undated (Box 5)
  - Congressional Record, Rape, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Conk, Margo, Surplus Value and the Secretary, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Connecticut Law Journal, Stern v. Stern, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Connecticut Legislation in Women, 2 folders, undated (Box 5)
  - Connecticut Task Force on Abused Women, Household Violence Study, undated (Box 5)
  - Consumption and Selling, From the Market Book, undated (Box 5)
  - Cook, Alice (Box 5)
    - Women and American Trade Unions, undated (Box 5)
    - Sex Discrimination at Universities: An Ombudsman’s View, undated (Box 5)
  - Cooper, Ann, Margaret Fuller, undated (Box 5)
  - Cooperstock, Ruth, Sex Differences in the Use of Mood-Modifying Drugs: An Explanatory Model, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Coser, Rose Laub and Gerald Rokoff, Women in the Occupational World: Social Disruption and Conflict, undated (Box 5)
  - Couchman, Lain Spencer Balfour, The Male Role in a ‘Liberated’ Household, undated (Box 5)
  - Cowley, Joyce, Pioneers of Women’s Liberation, undated (Box 5)
  - Cronan, Sheila, Marriage, undated (Box 5)
  - Crawford, Anne M., Bertha von Suttner: a Woman of Peace, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Cryan, Jeff, Trustees back Administration on Shea dismissal Decision, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Crowe, B. L., The Tragedy of the Commons Revisited, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Currier, Barbara, Special Approaches to Women's Education: A Model CoeducationBox 2, undated (Box 5)
  - Daniels, Arlene K., A Survey of Research Concerns on Women's Issues, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Dankert, Philip, Informational Item, undated (Box 5)
  - Davidovitch, David, Jewish Marriage Customs: Ketubot, Sivlonot and 'Marriage Stones', undated (Box 6)
  - Davis, Kingsley (Box 6)
    - Jealousy and Sexual Property, 1936 (Box 6)
    - The Pre-Hellenes, undated (Box 6)
  - Decko, Ruth, Response to Women's Liberation, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Degler, Carl N., What Ought to Be and What Was: Women's Sexuality in the Nineteenth Century, undated (Box 6)
  - Densmore, Dana, Sex Roles and Female Oppression, undated (Box 6)
  - Devlin, Karen and Robert, At Home in Russia with Three American Pre-Schoolers, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Dinerman, Beatrice, Attitudes and Practices towards Women in Architecture, Law, Engineering, Dentistry, undated (Box 6)
  - Dixon, Marlene, Why Women's Liberation?, undated (Box 6)
  - , A Documentary Herstory of Women Artists in Revolution, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Dodge, Norton, Women in the Soviet Economy, undated (Box 6)
  - Doubleday, Cathy, The Unimportance of Anatomy in Determining Children's Use of Space, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Dowd, Douglas, The Chick as Nigger, undated (Box 6)
  - Drew, Althea J., …Femininity is about as Ambiguous a Matter as Patriotism…, undated (Box 6)
  - Drinker, Cecil K., Not so Long Ago: Childbearing in 1790, 1937 (Box 6)
  - DuBois, Cora, The Dominant Value Profile of American Culture, undated (Box 6)
  - DuBois, Ellen, The Nineteenth Century Woman Suffrage Movement: Suffrage as a Total Ideology, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Duffey, Joseph, The Future of the Professoriate, undated (Box 6)
  - Dunning, Bob, Discrimination of Women in Sports, undated (Box Bpx 6)
  - Eagleton Institute of Politics, Letter(s) on Conference of Women State Legislators at Rutgers, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Eastwood, Mary, The Double Standard of Justice: Women's Rights Under the Constitution, undated (Box 6)
  - Edwards, Lee R., Jerusalem the Golden: A Fable for Our Times, undated (Box 6)
  - , War and Roses: A Dedication to Mrs Dalloway as a Political Novel, undated (Box 6)
  - Edwards, Ward and Lindman, Harold and Savage, Leonard J., Psychological Review, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Edwards, Ward, Tactical Note on the Relation between Scientific and Statistical Hypotheses, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Eisenberg, Leon, Student Unrest: Sources and Consequences, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Elbow, Peter, Real Learning and Nondisciplinary Courses, undated (Box 6)
  - Emmerich, Watter, Community Change in Sex-Role Development, undated (Box 6)
  - Engels, The Origins of the Family: Private Property and the State, undated (Box 6)
  - Ephron, Nora, The Bennington Affair, undated (Box 6)
  - Epstein, Cynthia F., Structuring Success for Women: Guidelines for Gatekeepers, undated (Box 7)
  - , Sex Role Stereotyping, Occupations and Social Exchange, undated (Box 7)
  - , Black and Female: The Double Whammy, undated (Box 7)
  - Equal Rights: National Women's Party,, undated (Box 7)
  - Eric Clearinghouse on Higher Education, The Status of Academic Women, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Erickson, Mildred, University College Quarterly, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Ermarth, Elizabeth, The Mill on the Floss, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Evans, Nancy B., The Political Consciousness of Virginia Woolf: A Room of One's Own and Three Guineas, undated (Box 7)
  - Fakunding, Lydia, Before the Wife of Bath: a Study of Women in Old English Poetry, undated (Box 7)
  - Farah, Barbara and Hoag, Wendy J., Preliminary Report on the Changing Status and Role of Women in Politics, undated (Box 7)
  - Farians, Elizabeth, Justice: The Hard Line (Andover Newton Quarterly), 1972 (Box 7)
  - , The Farians Vs. Loyola University (Chicago) Case, undated (Box 7)
  - , The Coming of Woman: The Christa, undated (Box 7)
  - , Women, Religion and the Law, undated (Box 7)
  - , The Human Dignity of Women in the Church, undated (Box 7)
  - , Population, Environment and Women, undated (Box 7)
  - , The Status of Women in the Church, undated (Box 7)
  - Farley, The New Feminist Movement and the Mass Magazines, undated (Box 7)
  - , Women in Academic Life, undated (Box 7)
  - , The Effect of Urbanization and the Role of Women, undated (Box 7)
  - Farrell, Warren, The Masculine Value System: Men Defining Reality ch 2, 1973 (Box 7)
  - , The Development of Masculinity, undated (Box 7)
  - , Guidelines for Consciousness-raising, undated (Box 7)
  - , The Resocialization of Men's Attitudes toward Women's Role in Society, undated (Box 7)
  - Fasteau, Marc F., The Male Machine, undated (Box 7)
  - , Why Aren't We Talking?, undated (Box 7)
  - , Clubishness, undated (Box 7)
  - Federal Laws and Regulations Concerning Sex Discrimination in Educational Institutions,, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Federationist, Women Workers: Profile of a Growing Force, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Feinblatt, Kaplan, Sex Role Alienation and Hospitalization, 1972 (Box 7)
  - , Sex Role Alienation in a Child Guidance Clinic, undated (Box 7)
  - The Female Experience,, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Fine-Knowles, Marjorie, Cases and Materials on Women and the Law, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Fiedler, Leslie, The Male Novel, undated (Box 7)
  - Filene, Peter, Men and Manliness Before WWI, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Firestone, Shulamith, On American Feminism, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Fisher, Elizabeth, Children's Books: The Second Sex, Junior Division, undated (Box 8)
  - Fleming, Thomas J., Sex and Civil Rights, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Flora, Cornelia B., The Passive Female: Her Comparative Image by Class and Culture in Women's Magazine Fiction, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Fogarty, Michal P., Book Review of Sex, Career and Family, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Ford, John H., Book: Husband and Father, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Forum, Special Edition: Women in the Labor Force, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Francis, Barbara, The Family and Social Change, undated (Box 8)
  - , The Status of Women at Cornell, undated (Box 8)
  - , Sexual Variations, undated (Box 8)
  - Frankfort, Ellen, Vaginal Politics, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Fraser, Dorothy B, Union Seminary Quarterly Review:: The Feminine Mystique: 1890-1910, undated (Box 8)
  - Fredriksson, Ingrid, Sex Roles and Education in Sweden, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Freedman, Monroe H., Equality: Men's Lib, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Freeman, Jo, The Building of the Guilded Cage, 1970-1975 (Box 8)
  - , The Feminist as Scholar, undated (Box 8)
  - , The Politics of Women's Liberation: The Roots of Revolt, undated (Box 8)
  - , The Social Construction of the Second Sex, undated (Box 8)
  - , The Legal Basis of the Sexual Caste System, undated (Box 8)
  - Friedan, Betty, Beyond Women's Liberation, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - , Up from the Kitchen Floor, undated (Box 8)
  - Freidland, Seymour J and Crockett, Walter H. and Laird, James D., The Effects of Role and Sex on the Perception of Others, undated (Box 8)
  - Fries, Maureen, "Slydinge of Corage"Chaucer's Criseyde as Feminist and Victim, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Fuchs, Nancy, No Trace, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Fuchs, Victor R., Short-Run and Long-Run Prospects for Female Earnings, undated (Box 8)
  - Gadol, Joan Kelly, The Effects of Women's History upon Traditional Histiography: Women in the Renaissance and Renaissance Histiography, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Gadol, Joan Kelly, History and the Social Relation of the Sexes, 1975 (Box 8)
  - , Universae Man, undated (Box 8)
  - , No Title, undated (Box 8)
  - Gadpaille, Warren J., Biological Fallacies of Women's Lib, undated (Box 8)